firstdatamerchantservices.com 2002-04-05

# 

Online Privacy Statement (www.fdms.com)

Our Commitment to Privacy

Thank you for visiting the First Data Merchant Services Corporation website. Protecting your privacy is very important to us. Our Online Privacy Statement is designed to inform you about our online collection and use of personal information. From time to time, First Data Merchant Services Corporation (referred to in this policy as "FDMS") may modify this Online Privacy Statement.

The Online Privacy Statement is available on the homepage of this web site as well as at every point where you provide us with personal information. From time to time, you may click to other FDMS web sites or pages that have different privacy policies. When this happens, you can review those privacy policies that relate to those pages or sites.

For more information about the FDMS commitment to protecting your privacy both online and offline, please read our Privacy Principles. 

_**The Only Personal Information We Collect Online is that Information You Voluntarily Provide to Us.  
**_

The only information we collect about you online is information that you voluntarily provide to us. This information may include, for example, company name or E-mail address. If you supply us with personal information on this web site, you will only be contacted so that we can provide you with the information you have requested or to occasionally send you other information about FDMS and its services that we believe you would find interesting.

**_When You Browse the FDMS Website, You Do So Without Revealing Your Identity._**

This FDMS web site uses cookies - which are identification files that track your web browsing activity - only to aggregate information about the sites that users visit so that we can update and redesign, as necessary, our web site in order to provide you with the most useful information. Personal information, such as your E-mail address, is not collected, unless you provide it to us. FDMS does not disclose domain name or aggregate information to third parties other than vendors who assist us with our web site and who are under strict confidentiality requirements. 

**_We Are Committed to Protecting the Confidentiality of Your Information._** __

FDMS' policies limit access to personal user information that is collected from this web site to only those employees of FDMS and its affiliates who need the information to fulfill their business responsibilities. FDMS may disclose personal user information collected online to companies affiliated with FDMS surrounding employment opportunities with other FDC operating companies. Vendors and other outside contractors we engage are subject to our contractual requirements to ensure that sensitive personal information is safeguarded. 

Employees must adhere to FDMS' Online Privacy Statement in addition to FDMS' Privacy Principles. Employees violating the FDMS Online Privacy Statement or the FDMS Privacy Principles are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including dismissal. 

_**We Give Consumers Choices about How Their Information Will be Used.**_

In some instances, if we collect consumer information online, we will inform users about how to remove their names from our lists:

  * Those submitting information to receive our press releases should call 954-227-6146 or E-mail [marilyn.proetto@firstdata.com](javascript:OpenMailWin\('/mail.asp?to=marilyn.proetto@firstdata.com','win'\)).
  * Those submitting resumes and other job-related information should E-mail/Fax to:

[employment.fdms@firstdata.com](javascript:OpenMailWin\('/mail.asp?to=employment.fdms@firstdata.com','win'\))   
**Fax: 631-843-6834**  
Phone: 631-843-6760   
**Please clearly reference job title or reference# with your submission**  
First Data Merchant Services  
Human Resources   
265 Broadhollow Road   
Melville, NY 11747 

**_We Use Appropriate Security Safeguards._**

At FDMS, security is a priority. FDMS employs appropriate measures, including advanced technology, to protect personal information collected online against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. These may include, among others, encryption, physical access security, and other appropriate technologies. FDMS continually reviews and enhances its security systems, as necessary.

**_We Maintain Procedures to Assure the Quality of Information We Collect and In Some Instances, We Inform Consumers About How They Can Access Their Information and Make Corrections, If Necessary._**

FDMS employs appropriate measures to assure the quality of information, which we collect directly from users online. Where information is collected by FDMS directly from users online, in some instances, FDMS informs users how to correct any erroneous or out-of-date information stored in our database. Where applicable, we abide by laws related to such information. 

_**FDMS' Website May Be Linked to Other Websites.**_

FDMS may create links to third-party websites. FDMS is not responsible for the content or privacy practices employed by websites that are linked to our website. 

**_FDMS' Website is Not Directed at Children Under the Age of 13._**

Our web site is not directed at children under the age of 13 and FDMS does not collect or maintain information at our website from children who we actually know are under the age of 13.

**_We Hold Ourselves Accountable Under Our Privacy Principles._**

FDMS is committed to meeting the highest standards for our privacy program. A senior First Data Corporation (the parent company of FDMS) official serves as the company-wide privacy officer with responsibility for administering the First Data Corporation privacy program, including implementation of this Online Privacy Statement. 

The First Data Corporation privacy officer, working closely with First Data's subsidiaries, including FDMS, is responsible for:

  * Overseeing employee privacy training and employee compliance related to the Online Privacy Statement; 
  * Conducting periodic assessments of FDMS' compliance with this Online Privacy Statement, as well as specific implementation policies and procedures; and 
  * Ensuring that FDMS actively participates in appropriate privacy activities, including self-regulatory initiatives.

If you have any questions or comments about the FDMS Online Privacy Statement, please contact: Debbie Mosbacher via E-mail at [debbie.mosbacher@firstdata.com](javascript:OpenMailWin\('/mail.asp?to=debbie.mosbacher@firstdata.com','win'\)).

This FDMS online privacy statement is currently applicable to only U.S. customers and visitors to this website. International businesses may have their own rules and practices, which are consistent with their own privacy statements. They may alter their statements as needed for certain products/services and to abide by local laws and customs. 

First Data Merchant Services Corporation ("FDMS")   
Privacy Principles

As a world leader in electronic commerce and payment services, FDMS processes the information that enables businesses and consumers to pay for goods and services by credit, debit or stored-value cards at the point of sale. 

FDMS works behind the scenes on behalf of its alliances, banks, other card acquirers and merchants. As the internet continues to play a greater role in commerce and payments, FDMS will continue to develop solutions that enable businesses and consumers to pay anyone, anywhere, anytime. 

Millions of consumers and businesses rely on FDMS, and our client partners, for safe and reliable payment services. Our relationships are established based on mutual trust. Each day, we - and our more than 9,000 employees \- strive to reinforce our commitment to our business customers and consumers. 

In order to provide these services, FDMS must collect, maintain and use financial and other sensitive personal information. 

FDMS' Privacy Principles guide us in the collection and use of information and reinforce the role our employees play in protecting consumer privacy. 

Our business customers and alliances may adopt other principles applicable to their collection and use of information or simply customize these principles.

**_FDMS Privacy Principles_**

  1. **_WE OBTAIN PERSONAL INFORMATION THAT IS NEEDED TO PROVIDE OUR GOODS AND SERVICES._ **

We primarily receive personal information as a result of consumers' financial transactions with FDMSSM or with FDMS business customers and alliances. Generally, FDMS does not obtain personal information directly from consumers. However, when FDMS collects information directly from consumers, we obtain the personal information that is needed to provide our goods or services, to provide customer service and to fulfill any legal or regulatory requirements. When we obtain information about consumers from third parties, we use reputable sources, including public repositories.

  2. **_WE WILL INFORM CONSUMERS ABOUT THE GENERAL USES OF THEIR INFORMATION._ **

Generally, FDMS does not have a direct customer relationship with consumers. However, when we have a direct relationship with consumers, we will strive to make information available to them about the general uses of the information that we collect. Generally, FDMS obtains personal information about consumers indirectly through our business customers and channels. To that end, we encourage our business customers and channels to provide these consumers with a timely and complete privacy notice. 

  3. **_WE USE CONSUMER INFORMATION IN A MANNER WHICH IS CONSISTENT WITH OUR PRIVACY NOTICE._**

FDMS uses information only in a manner consistent with our privacy notice. Protecting consumer privacy is very important as we build trusted relationships and assist businesses and consumers in conducting sensitive and wide-ranging electronic commerce activities. 

  4. **_WE ARE COMMITTED TO PROTECTING THE CONFIDENTIALITY OF PERSONAL CONSUMER INFORMATION._**

Within FDMS, access to personal information is limited to those employees of FDMS and its affiliates who need it to fulfill their business responsibilities. 

When FDMS collects information on behalf of our business customers and alliances, we handle the information based on their direction and in accordance with our agreements and contracts with them and applicable laws.

Vendors and other outside contractors we engage are subject to our contractual requirements to ensure sensitive personal information is safeguarded. 

  5. **_WE STRIVE TO GIVE CONSUMERS CHOICES ABOUT HOW THEIR DATA WILL BE USED._**

If we obtain personal information as part of our direct relationship with consumers, we will not share this information with non-affiliated third parties except in accordance with these Privacy Principles; to facilitate and complete consumer-initiated or authorized transactions; to comply with federal, state and local laws, including credit reporting laws and card association rules; to combat fraud; or to offer products and services that FDMS believes may be of interest to its customers. Upon request, we will allow consumers to remove their names from any FDMS-owned marketing lists.

  6. **_WE USE APPROPRIATE SECURITY SAFEGUARDS._**

At FDMS, security is a priority. We employ appropriate measures to protect consumer information against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. These may include, among others, encryption, physical access security and other appropriate technologies. FDMS continually reviews and enhances its security systems, as necessary.

  7. **_WE MAINTAIN PROCEDURES TO ASSURE THE QUALITY OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND WHERE APPLICABLE, WE WILL INFORM CONSUMERS ABOUT HOW THEY CAN ACCESS THEIR PERSONAL INFORMATION AND MAKE CORRECTIONS, IF NECESSARY._**

Generally, FDMS does not collect personal information directly from consumers. However, where information is collected by FDMS directly from consumers, we permit them to review and, if possible, dispute or correct any erroneous or out-of-date information stored in our database, which is retrievable on a personally identifiable basis. (Of course, this review and correction would not be possible if the information is proprietary to one of our business customers or if access would violate the privacy or legal rights of a third party).

  8. **_WE HOLD OURSELVES ACCOUNTABLE TO OUR PRIVACY PRINCIPLES._**

FDMS is committed to meeting the highest standards for our privacy program. A senior FDMS official serves as the company-wide privacy officer, with responsibility for administering the FDMS privacy program, including implementation of these Privacy Principles. 

The FDMS privacy officer is responsible for:

  * administering employee privacy training and employee compliance programs related to the Privacy Principles. 
  * conducting periodic assessments of FDMS' compliance with these Privacy Principles, as well as specific implementation policies and procedures. 
  * ensuring that First Data actively participates in appropriate privacy activities, including self-regulatory initiatives.

If you have any questions or comments about the FDMS Privacy Principles, please contact: 

Debbie Mosbacher  
First Data Merchant Services Corporation  
(281) 346-0616  
[debbie.mosbacher@firstdata.com](javascript:OpenMailWin\('/mail.asp?to=debbie.mosbacher@firstdata.com','win'\))
